<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>projects on 1ar.io</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
        <description>Recent content in projects on 1ar.io</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Pavel Larionov</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>book ｢ Dying in 2045 ｣</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/dying-2045/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/dying-2045/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/projects/dying-2045/smartphone-grave.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post book ｢ Dying in 2045 ｣" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;what&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dying in 2045&amp;rdquo; (original German: &amp;ldquo;Wie werden wir in Zukunft sterben?&amp;rdquo;) offers an insightful outlook into a future where technology and society have evolved together, profoundly affecting how we live and eventually die. The book explores the deep integration of digitalization in our daily lives, touching on its historical roots and potential trajectory towards 2045.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From book&amp;rsquo;s official description:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How will we treat dying, death and mourning individually, socially and institutionally in 2045, how will needs and expectations develop? Will the trend towards individualization, isolation and dying in care facilities continue? What impact will digitalization have? Experts from various fields of action and scientific disciplines develop scenarios for how dying, death and mourning will be organized in the future. They open up &amp;ldquo;desirable&amp;rdquo; perspectives and show what needs to be done to make them a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter I was honored to work on: &amp;ldquo;Digitalization, Scenarios of a digitalized society&amp;rdquo;. It delves into the concept of true digitalization, distinguishing it from mere digital mimicry and underscoring its transformative impact across various domains, including healthcare, consumer trends, and end-of-life experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/dying-2045/cover_front.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;3024&#34;
	height=&#34;4032&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/dying-2045/cover_front_hu0fe5f15035e89835aeb2586ca521296f_989091_480x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/projects/dying-2045/cover_front_hu0fe5f15035e89835aeb2586ca521296f_989091_1024x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;book cover, front&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;75&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;180px&#34;
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/dying-2045/cover-back.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;3024&#34;
	height=&#34;4032&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/dying-2045/cover-back_hu31c0ccc4b1a2d4d9bbee3dd7ee9b2b34_975693_480x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/projects/dying-2045/cover-back_hu31c0ccc4b1a2d4d9bbee3dd7ee9b2b34_975693_1024x0_resize_q75_box.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;book cover, back&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;75&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;180px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-chapter&#34;&gt;my chapter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Larionov, P. (2023). Szenarien einer digitalisierten Gesellschaft. In Psychosozial-Verlag eBooks (pp. 297–312). &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.30820/9783837961058-297&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://doi.org/10.30820/9783837961058-297&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is in German, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to publish a raw, unedited by co-authors english version &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/dying-2045-digital/&#34; &gt;here on my website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;chapters-overview&#34;&gt;chapter&amp;rsquo;s overview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/dying-2045-digital/#introduction&#34; &gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;: Sets the stage by reflecting on digitalization&amp;rsquo;s historical roots and its profound influence on society. This chapter contemplates the profound changes digitalization has brought, starting from Morse code to AI-driven technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/dying-2045-digital/#currently-existing-trends-in-technology-and-digitalization&#34; &gt;Currently Existing Trends in Technology and Digitalization&lt;/a&gt;: Examines current technological trends and their implications. Focuses on the status quo of technology, particularly in healthcare and consumer products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/dying-2045-digital/#true-digitalization&#34; &gt;True Digitalization&lt;/a&gt;: Differentiates between superficial digital mimicry and genuine, transformative digitalization. Explores the evolution of digitalization from initial replication of physical entities to fully realized digital integration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/dying-2045-digital/#consumer-trends&#34; &gt;Consumer Trends&lt;/a&gt;: Discusses current trends in consumer technology, particularly health tracking and digital healthcare apps. Analyzes current consumer technologies like health tracking wearables and digital healthcare apps, highlighting their benefits and shortcomings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/dying-2045-digital/#consumer-trends&#34; &gt;Upcoming Trends&lt;/a&gt;: Predicts future developments in IT corporations, digital healthcare, AI in mental health, the metaverse, and blockchain in healthcare. Looks at future prospects, including IT giants entering healthcare, AI in mental health, metaverse development, and blockchain&amp;rsquo;s potential in healthcare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/dying-2045-digital/#end-of-life&#34; &gt;End of Life&lt;/a&gt;: Explores how digital advancements might alter perceptions and experiences of death. Speculates on how technology might transform our experience of death, including digital avatars and virtual reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;full-book&#34;&gt;full book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wie werden wir in Zukunft sterben? (2023). In Psychosozial-Verlag eBooks. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.30820/9783837961058&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://doi.org/10.30820/9783837961058&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can buy your copy directly on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.psychosozial-verlag.de/catalog/product_info.php/products_id/6105&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Psychosozial-Verlag website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;my role&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the researchers and authors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created web presence for the project: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sterben-tod-trauer-2045.de/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://sterben-tod-trauer-2045.de/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created the artwork for the book cover and for the project&amp;rsquo;s webpage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where--with-whom&#34;&gt;where / with whom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was invited to work on the chapter by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://wolfgang-george.de/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Prof. Dr. Wolfgang George&lt;/a&gt;. Full list of authors (29 in total):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tatjana Ahle-Rosental, Thorsten Benkel, Eckhard Dommer, Annette Franke, Wolfgang George, Paul Herrlein, Johannes Herrmann, Ulrike Kempchen, Johanna Klug, David Kröll, Pavel Larionov, Eberhard Lux, Barbara Meyer-Zehnder, Elmar Nass, Jens Papke, Hans Pargger, Dirk Pörschmann, Lena Reseck, Karl-Christian Schelzke, Heike Seeliger, Thomas Sitte, Elke Steudter, Elisabeth Vanderheiden, Karsten Weber, Conrad Wesch, Christoph Wiese und Volker Ziegler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when&#34;&gt;when&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written in May-October 2022, printed and published in September 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what&#34;&gt;so what?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dying in 2045&amp;rdquo; paints a vivid picture of a future where digital technology is deeply woven into our social fabric. It predicts significant transformations in healthcare, consumer behavior, and even our understanding of life and death. The book encourages readers to consider how these advancements might shape not just technology but our very humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my chapter, I predicted (the book was published in 2023, but all the drafts were ready more than year ago - editing and finalization takes time) the emergence of the next-level chatbots and their application as therapists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>project ｢ The Truth Wins ｣</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/the-truth-wins/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/the-truth-wins/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/projects/the-truth-wins/ttw-square.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post project ｢ The Truth Wins ｣" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what---bypassing-censorship-with-cutting-edge-technology&#34;&gt;what - bypassing censorship with cutting edge technology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem - governments are demanding social networks to ban (or shadowban) certain journalists, activists, opposition politics etc. The followers of such people will need to research where to follow this person, which leads to inevitable lost of reach. To address this issue without asking for permission of neither government nor social media companies (because censorship should not thrive in our internet), a two fold solution was made as part of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.the-truth-wins.com/en/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Truth Wins&lt;/a&gt; campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first solution - initial brief idea - to hack national lotteries results and use it as a universal identificator. This identificator is used by journalists as part of their handle. As national lotteries are held on regular basis and the winning numbers can be found really easy, those numbers can be used to find all banned accounts on a social network. So governments can demand social network to ban certain people as much as they want, the banned user can just create new account and followers will find it in no time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second solution is even more straightforward for the end users. There are ways how you can use blockchain to bypass censorship: provide redirection to a classic domain name or store the content itself on decentralized storage. The redirection part uses blockchain-based DNS provider (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ens.domains/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ENS&lt;/a&gt; - ethereum name service) and the content storing part involves decentralized storage solution is for example &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ipfs.tech/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; (interplanetary file system).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with redirection part. As it is hardly possible to block a blockchain-based name resolver (internet service provider would need to block all traffic to the blockchain - e.g. ethereum - network) and it is fairly easy to replace the target, this makes the URL to certain website virtually invincible. So user can just bookmark this URL and it will redirect to the currently active domain of the resource you are trying to reach. Think of the Pirate Bay torrent tracker - they are always changing domain name to avoid being blocked, but you need to search for the current name, as you bookmark won&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to the storage part. If certain lightweight content (text with minimal images) need to be protected from censorship, it can be stored on the decentralized storage, e.g. IPFS. It needs to be lightweight because the access speed is not the fastest. Such content will profit from the similar benefits as blockchain-based domain name resolver in terms of invulnarability - in order to block such content the ISP would need to bring down all nodes serving IPFS. So in combination with a decentralized domain - it will take A LOT of efforts from IPS side to bring your website down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the lottery-numbers part is obviously an amazing idea, I was much more excited by the blockchain part because of the relative ease of use for the end users and scalability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Truth Wins is the showcase of how blockchain can go beyond speculation towards freedom of speech and truly borderless journalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/enGJmBM4DHE&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;my role&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was curating the website development as creative technologist and was in charge of the implementation of the blockchain part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where--with-whom&#34;&gt;where / with whom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was fulfilled by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hyperinteractive.de/the-truth-wins/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hyperinteractive Innovation Studio&lt;/a&gt; in collaboration with DDB agency, who delivered the initial lottery-numbers idea. The idea to add blockchain to the package was initially suggested by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.saurabhkakade.com/projects/the-truth-wins&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Saurabh Kakade&lt;/a&gt;, a talanted art director who worked at Hyperinteractive back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when&#34;&gt;when&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spring 2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what&#34;&gt;so what?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The campaign achieved a huge reach - +150k followers on the_truth_wins accounts on twitter, large press coverage (85+ news articles), +39% donations to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reporter-ohne-grenzen.de/aktivitaeten/kampagnen/the-truth-wins&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Reporters Without Borders&lt;/a&gt; non-profit organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally was instantly fascinated by the idea of the project, as I am not a fan of censorship, to say the least. I am also very fond of meaningful application of technology, so using blockchain in a not obvious way was a pure pleasure.
We were happy to know, that the idea and our implementation was positively received by the international community, so we scored 24 awards, including several golden ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>project ｢ Avenue-Pal ｣ IT and Palliative Care</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/avenue-pal/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/avenue-pal/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/projects/avenue-pal/ap.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post project ｢ Avenue-Pal ｣ IT and Palliative Care" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;what&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project Avenue-Pal aimed to improve palliative care from three angles: hospitals, nursing homes and caregivers. In particular, metrics to optimize were the transfers, which often happen in the last phase of life (e.g. transfer of a terminally ill patient from a nursing home to a hospital). While overall goal was to develop a series of guidelines which hospitals, healthcare professionals and nursing home personal can follow, I was particularly involved in the development of an IT systems which would support the initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of the sub-project &amp;ldquo;Solution for Information &amp;amp; Communication&amp;rdquo; was to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simplify guidelines implementation on sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;empower caregivers in the system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both targets were addressed by developing systems to deliver adequate information to the right actors or participants at the right time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;my role&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project engineer at first, IT project lead short after the project began. I was leading team of developers, who was working on prototypes for the informational systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;where--with-whom&#34;&gt;where / with whom&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Institute for Biomedical Technology at the University of Applied Sciences Mittelhessen in collaboration with TransMIT GmbH (Giessen), University Clinic of Giessen and Marburg and AWO Giessen (a nursing home).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;when&#34;&gt;when&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019-2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-what&#34;&gt;so what?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project delivered two prototypes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital guideline implementation system, which could potentially replace hardly readable plain-texts issued by govermental bodies.
The system consisted of an assessment part, informational part and tracking part. The workflow of any institution, which would use the system would be streamlined, as it gave portionized information in correct order about which aspects in the institution need to be addressed in order to comply with the new set of guidelines. The system was tested in the partners institution and described helpful and time-saving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An iOS and Android app for caregivers, which proved itself useful during user tests by healthcare professionals and caregivers.
The app contained curated and granularly prepared pieces of information, so that every situation can be assessed and assisted. It also has provided a way to store the data in FHIR format - so potentially compatible with other medical systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the project was funded by GBA (Federal Joint Cometee - curates public health sector), all developments and documentation were handed over to the GBA and DLR (German Center of Airospace Flights, which also curates innovations in biomedical and healthcare spheres).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>project ｢ Dot Go ｣</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/dot-go/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/dot-go/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/projects/dot-go/dot-all.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post project ｢ Dot Go ｣" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dot Go is an &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dot-go.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;iOS app&lt;/a&gt; for visually impaired persons, which helps users identify objects and trigger actions. The core idea of the app is simple yet powerful - &lt;code&gt;real objects trigger actions&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone&amp;rsquo;s LiDAR to estimate the distance to the object accurately&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;computer vision algorithms to recognize common objects in the surroundings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workflow of the app:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a target object (e.g., socks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up a scenario (e.g., play sound)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Optionally - run shortcut, e.g., check out an item in Apple Reminders)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IGdrJhuOo9A&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, as soon as a target object is recognized (user points smartphone at socks), the action is initiated (sound is played, and reminder is checked out). So a hypothetical user can now make lists of things easily, which is especially useful in, for example, unknown environments (while travelling).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The computer vision algorithm is optimized to work on-device, so no internet and no external API are required to use the app. The UI of the app is built and implemented by following accessibility guidelines, which were tested by real users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;My Role&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined the project as a creative technologist when a proof of concept was done, but the requirements changed and the quality had to increase. So my first task was to redefine the scope, the metrics, and the desired outcome and get all stakeholders aligned about the new course of actions. Based on the created documentation, we decided to refresh the design and upgrade our object recognition algorithms, while having usability by the target audience (visually impaired users) as our main priority. After several sporty sprints, during which I led the developers team and kept in touch with designers and the agency, we rebuilt the app and delivered the project on time and in the required quality to the stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where--with-whom&#34;&gt;Where / With Whom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app was implemented by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hyperinteractive.de/dot-go/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hyperinteractive Innovative Studio&lt;/a&gt; in collaboration with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://l2-labs.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;L2-Labs&lt;/a&gt; company. The product was created by the initiative of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.dotincorp.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Dot Inc.&lt;/a&gt; - an innovative Korean accessibility-focused company and a creative agency, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.house-of-communication.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Serviceplan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when&#34;&gt;When&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined the project in October 2020 (the project started in mid 2020) and was finished in Spring 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what&#34;&gt;So What?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app won a relatively large number of awards (32), including the Eurobest Grand Prix and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ifdesign.com/en/winner-ranking/project/dot-go/568645&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;iF design award&lt;/a&gt;, and won in multiple categories on various international platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>project ｢ Spike Sorting ｣ Multivariate Data</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/spike-sorting-multivariate/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/spike-sorting-multivariate/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/projects/spike-sorting-multivariate/neuron-high.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post project ｢ Spike Sorting ｣ Multivariate Data" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;what&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automated classification of waveforms is an important method of data processing used in various fields of science, such as neuroscience, biomedical engineering, etc. This work shows the possibility of sorting special waveforms i.e. spikes recorded with multichannel electrode arrays by using principles of correlation and data-driven reference. A new method to estimate the number of k-means clusters by using a Monte Carlo method is introduced. To demonstrate the performance of the algorithm, generated signals were used, which are created to mimic multichannel recording of the extra-cellular neuronal signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Larionov, P., Juergens, T. &amp;amp; Schanze, T. (2019). Correlation-based spike sorting of multivariate data. Current Directions in Biomedical Engineering, 5(1), pp. 113-116. Retrieved 2 Oct. 2019, [](from doi:10.1515/cdbme-2019-0029)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;my role&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main author and developer, project leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;where--with-whom&#34;&gt;where / with whom&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-created in collaboration with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tom-j%C3%BCrgens-752a58188/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Tom Jürgens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
Institute of the Biomedical Technology, IBMT, University of Applied Sciences.&lt;br&gt;
Scientific group of Prof. Dr. Thomas Schanze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;when&#34;&gt;when&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-what&#34;&gt;so what?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publication was presented by me during the scientific conference &amp;ldquo;Current Direction in Biomedical Engineering&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>paper ｢ Places of Death Register ｣</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/death-register-germany/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/death-register-germany/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;what&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, only deaths in hospitals are reported, which is seen as inadequate for health research and planning. The register was suggested in the paper, which would benefit various groups, including quality management, health system designers, citizens, and service providers. It could also uphold the moral principles of medical care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;George, W., Fritz, T., Papke, J., Weber, K., &amp;amp; Larionov, P. (2019). Braucht die Versorgungsforschung in Deutschland ein Sterbeortregister? in Monitor Versorgungsforschung (06/19), S. 57-60 doi: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.monitor-versorgungsforschung.de/abstract/braucht-die-versorgungsforschung-in-deutschland-ein-sterbeortregister/?cookie-state-change=1701386391787&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;10.24945/MVF.06.19.1866-0533.2191&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/death_places_registry.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Image: Death Registry Architecture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;my role&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-author, data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;where--with-whom&#34;&gt;where / with whom&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;George, W., Fritz, T., Papke, J., Weber, K&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;when&#34;&gt;when&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-what&#34;&gt;so what?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we think that government has it all figured out, as well as the healthcare professionals. But then you find out that one or another obvious construct does not exist even as concept.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>project ｢ Spike Sorting ｣ Adaptation for ECG</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/spike-sorting-ecg/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/spike-sorting-ecg/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/projects/spike-sorting-ecg/ecg.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post project ｢ Spike Sorting ｣ Adaptation for ECG" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;what&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An adaptation of a spike sorting algorithm (published &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/spike-sorting&#34; &gt;earlier&lt;/a&gt; by our research group) was performed in order to analyze ECG.
Preliminary results show that a “spike sorting” of single ECG signals is possible, i.e. a sorting of P-waves, QRScomplexes, and T-waves. The clustering results indicate that differentiation between normal and anomalous P-waves, QRS-complexes, and T-waves is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Larionov, P., Janssen J.-D. and Schanze T. (2018). Adaption of a spike sorting algorithm to ECG
signals. Abstracts - BMT 2018 – Aachen, September 26–28, Biomedical Engineering /
Biomedizinische Technik, Volume 63, Issue s1, Page 394, ISSN (Online) 1862-278X, ISSN (Print)
0013-5585, DOI: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1515/bmt-2018-6051&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://doi.org/10.1515/bmt-2018-6051&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;my role&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main author and developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where--with-whom&#34;&gt;where / with whom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-created in collaboration with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jdjanssen/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jan-Dirk Janssen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
Institute of the Biomedical Technology, IBMT, University of Applied Sciences.&lt;br&gt;
Scientific group of Prof. Dr. Thomas Schanze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when&#34;&gt;when&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what&#34;&gt;so what?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De Gruyter · Sep 1, 2018
Publication was published as part of BMT 2018 scientific conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>project ｢ Spike Sorting ｣</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/spike-sorting/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/spike-sorting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/projects/spike-sorting/neuron.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post project ｢ Spike Sorting ｣" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;what&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultimate goal of the spike sorting is to allocate a signal with a source. An algorithm which can effectively perform this task can be applied in wide variety of spheres, but we have selected as our target area the field of neuroscience. As the spike sorting is the first step to study brain and develop a brain-computer interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goal of the project: development of an easy-to-use, resource-saving and fast algorithm of spike sorting, based on the calculation of correlations of spikes’ waveforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Larionov, P. and Schanze T. (2018). Correlation Based Spike Sorting. Automed 2018 - Villingen-
Schwenningen, March 15-16, Automed 2018 in Villingen-Schwenningen Tagungsband, pp. 71-73.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;my role&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main author and developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;where--with-whom&#34;&gt;where / with whom&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Institute of the Biomedical Technology, IBMT, University of Applied Sciences.&lt;br&gt;
Scientific group of Prof. Dr. Thomas Schanze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;when&#34;&gt;when&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018-2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-what&#34;&gt;so what?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publication was presented by me during Automed 2018 scientific conference. The project became foundational for the series of publication, done by me and other researchers of the scientific group, e.g. to apply the algorithm for &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/spike-sorting-ecg&#34; &gt;ECG analysis&lt;/a&gt;. The algorithm capabilities were significantly improved by introduction of the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/spike-sorting-multivariate/&#34; &gt;multivariate mode&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
